<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Set up DNS :: book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-dns/index.html</link>
    <description>Before you can configure any hardware, you need to set up the domain name service (DNS) of your domain.&#xA;Index Register a domain name Add the domain to DigitalOcean DNS Generate DigitalOcean API token for ACME challenge </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-dns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Register a domain name</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-dns/register-domain/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-dns/register-domain/index.html</guid>
      <description>To host a web service, one of the first things you will need is to register your domain name (e.g., example.com). This will be the domain name used for all of your service links, and it is what your users will need to type into their web browsers (or click on) to visit your pages.&#xA;Public domain names are a scarce resource. Because of their scarcity, you must pay for your domain registrations, doing so in 1 year increments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Add the domain to DigitalOcean DNS</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-dns/create-digitalocean-api-token/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-dns/create-digitalocean-api-token/index.html</guid>
      <description>The Domain Name System is how you can associate one of your sub-domains with an actual IP address on the Internet.&#xA;Choose a supported DNS provider This book uses DigitalOcean as the DNS provider in all examples, but you may choose a different provider if you prefer, but it needs to be supported by go-acme LEGO.&#xA;Sign up for a DigitalOcean account (using this referral link helps support this site), and follow along to set up your domain’s DNS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generate DigitalOcean API token for ACME challenge</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-dns/create-digitalocean-api-token-for-acme-challenge/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-dns/create-digitalocean-api-token-for-acme-challenge/index.html</guid>
      <description>Choose a supported DNS provider This book uses DigitalOcean as the DNS provider in all examples, but you may choose a different provider if you prefer, but it needs to be supported by go-acme LEGO.&#xA;DNS is also a part of the TLS certificate request process (ACME DNS-01 challenge). You will need to procure a DigitalOcean Personal Access Token, which is used for programatic control of your DigitalOcean account’s DNS settings on your behalf:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>