<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Set up DNS :: book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-dns/index.html</link>
    <description>Before you can configure any hardware, you need to set up the domain name service (DNS) of your domain.&#xA;Index Register a domain name Add the domain to DigitalOcean DNS Generate DigitalOcean API token for ACME challenge </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-dns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Register a domain name</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-dns/register-domain/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-dns/register-domain/index.html</guid>
      <description>To host a web service, one of the first things you will need to do is to register your domain name (e.g., example.com). This will be the root domain name used for all of your service links and it is part of what your users will need to type into their web browsers (or click on) to visit your pages.&#xA;--- title: A web browser must query DNS before it can fetch any web page --- sequenceDiagram participant Browser as Web Browser participant DNS as DNS Server participant WEB as Web Server Browser-&gt;&gt;DNS: DNS Request (Resolve domain name) DNS--&gt;&gt;Browser: DNS Response (IP Address) Browser-&gt;&gt;WEB: HTTP Request (Fetch Web Page) WEB--&gt;&gt;Browser: HTTP Response (Web Page Content) Domain name registration The public domain name registration system is controlled as a scarce resource that you must pay for the use of.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Add the domain to DigitalOcean DNS</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-dns/create-digitalocean-api-token/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-dns/create-digitalocean-api-token/index.html</guid>
      <description>The Domain Name System is how you associate your (sub-)domains with an actual IP address on the Internet.&#xA;Choose any supported DNS provider All examples in this book use DigitalOcean as the DNS provider. You may choose any DNS service that provides a programmatic API supported by go-acme LEGO.&#xA;Sign up for a DigitalOcean account (using this referral link helps support this site), and follow along to set up your domain’s DNS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generate DigitalOcean API token for ACME challenge</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-dns/create-digitalocean-api-token-for-acme-challenge/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-dns/create-digitalocean-api-token-for-acme-challenge/index.html</guid>
      <description>--- title: ACME challenge response for requesting a TLS certificate --- sequenceDiagram participant Traefik as Traefik (Docker) participant LE as Let&#39;s Encrypt (ACME) participant DO as DigitalOcean DNS Traefik-&gt;&gt;LE: Request / Renew TLS Certificate (ACME) LE--&gt;&gt;Traefik: Issue DNS-01 Challenge Traefik-&gt;&gt;DO: Update DNS Records using API token (Add TXT Record) DO--&gt;&gt;LE: DNS Challenge Resolved (TXT Record Found) LE--&gt;&gt;Traefik: Issue TLS Certificate Choose any supported DNS provider All examples in this book use DigitalOcean as the DNS provider.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>