<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/index.html</link>
    <description>This repository contains a collection of books written by EnigmaCurry.&#xA;This content is open-source, CC BY 4.0. See LICENSE for attribution rules.&#xA;Navigation This website is presented as a book of books, so you can read everything from beginning to end. Use your keyboard left/right arrow keys to flip through the pages.&#xA;If you are using a touch screen interface, use the arrow buttons at the top right of the page.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linux Workstation</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/index.html</guid>
      <description>This book describes how I setup a Linux Workstation (on a personal Desktop or Laptop computer).&#xA;Index Introduction Fedora Sway Atomic Requirements Install Linux (Fedora Atomic) Upgrading Layering packages Config Sway Firefox Toolbox Emacs SSH Solokey authentication Get your Solokey Solokey v2 Solokey v1 Sudo with Solokey SSH with Solokey Application users DigitalOcean CLI (doctl) KVM / libvirt Install libvirtd Setup libvirtd Create VM admin Cloud-Init VMs Configure VM (cloud-init) Create VM (cloud-init) Systemd services to control VMs Public routes to VMs Setup workstation SSH config </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-hosting Docker with d.rymcg.tech</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/index.html</guid>
      <description>This book describes how to get started with self-hosting your own Docker server, using the tools provided by d.rymcg.tech.&#xA;d.rymcg.tech Chat with us on Matrix Index Introduction Required Infrastructure Register a domain name Setup public DNS service Create a public server (VPS) Create a private server (libvirt VM) Setup your workstation Install Docker client tools Install d.rymcg.tech tools Setup Docker context Create SSH config and Docker context Install Docker on your remote host Setup d.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publishing with org-mode, ox-hugo, and literate programming.</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/publishing-with-org-mode/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/publishing-with-org-mode/index.html</guid>
      <description>This book describes how this site is written, in Org-mode, with ox-hugo, and bits of Literate Programming.&#xA;Index Dependencies Building locally Publishing with GitHub pages Publishing with SFTP Using Org-mode and Emacs Navigating Org-mode files Editing Org-mode files Example Org / Hugo content Example Org Blocks Example Shortcodes Example of a deeply … Nested … Sub-chapter 1 Sub-chapter 2 Sub-chapter 3 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LICENSE</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/license/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/license/index.html</guid>
      <description>book.rymcg.tech is © 2023, 2024 EnigmaCurry.&#xA;Except as listed below, all books and other files in this domain and/or git repository are licensed: Creative Commons Attribution 4.0. You can reference this repository like this, or by any other content equivalent custom formatting:&#xA;book.rymcg.tech is © 2024 EnigmaCurry used by permission CC BY 4.0See the full CC BY license at http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0&#xA;Exceptions The compiled/rendered HTML site uses hugo-theme-relearn which is distributed under the MIT license:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>