<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux Workstation :: book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/index.html</link>
    <description>This book describes how I setup a Linux Workstation (on a personal Desktop or Laptop computer).&#xA;Index Introduction Fedora Sway Atomic Requirements Install Linux (Fedora Atomic) Upgrading Layering packages Solokey authentication Solokey v1 Get your Solokey (v1) Install Solokey CLI (v1) tool Update your Solokey (v1) Program your Solokey (v1) Sudo with Solokey SSH with Solokey Application users DigitalOcean app user (doctl) Config Sway Firefox Toolbox Emacs SSH KVM / libvirt Install libvirtd Setup libvirtd Create VM admin Configure VM Create VM Systemd services to control VMs Public routes to VMs Setup workstation SSH config </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/introduction/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/introduction/index.html</guid>
      <description>A Linux Workstation is a single user computer that you use as your primary interface for computing, especially for “work” purposes. At a bare minimum, a workstation includes a keyboard and a display (although a workstation could also be a VPS that you SSH into, this book will focus on physical workstations).&#xA;Historically, there has been a hardware distinction between a personal computer (PC) and a Unix workstation, but ever since the introduction of Linux, the difference in hardware doesn’t really exist anymore, and any computing device can become a workstation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install Linux (Fedora Atomic)</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/install/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/install/index.html</guid>
      <description>Create USB installation media Download the Fedora Sway Atomic iso image. Assuming you are temporarily using another Linux workstation, write the .iso image to a USB drive:&#xA;[bash]: Run this on your workstation: dd if=Fedora-Sericea-ostree-x86_64-40-1.14.iso \ of=/dev/sdX bs=10M status=progress conv=sync Info Replace /dev/sdX with your device name, and double check the .iso filename, it may have changed.&#xA;Boot the target workstation computer using the USB drive. You will boot into the Anaconda install wizard.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/upgrading/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/upgrading/index.html</guid>
      <description>As mentioned before, Fedora Atomic is distributed as a full system image. You can both upgrade the image, as well as rollback the image (in case you have any issues with the upgrade.)&#xA;To upgrade to the latest image:&#xA;[bash]: Run this on your workstation: sudo rpm-ostree upgrade Let it finish downloading the new image, and then you must reboot:&#xA;[bash]: Run this on your workstation: sudo systemctl reboot The boot manager lists the last several images, which are still available to choose from.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Layering packages</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/layering-packages/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/layering-packages/index.html</guid>
      <description>See the Fedora docs for Adding Layered Packages. For most packages, you should not install them this way, but you should prefer installing them inside of a toolbox / distrobox container instead. On the Fedora Atomic host, you should install (layer) only those packages that cannot be run from a container (or you really just want to run them natively for some reason).&#xA;To create efficient layers, you should try to install everything in one go, using as few layers as possible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solokey authentication</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/sudo-2fa/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/sudo-2fa/index.html</guid>
      <description>Solokeys are physical hardware authentication (U2F / FIDO2) devices, that you plug into a USB port, which stores a secret key that can be used as primary or secondary authentication factors (2FA), with websites (Webauthn), and machines (sudo and SSH).&#xA;There are two versions of solokey now, v1 and v2, and they require separate toolchains. The instructions diverge here depending on which hardware revision you have.&#xA;Index Solokey v1 Get your Solokey (v1) Install Solokey CLI (v1) tool Update your Solokey (v1) Program your Solokey (v1) Sudo with Solokey SSH with Solokey </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application users</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/app-users/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/app-users/index.html</guid>
      <description>With strong authentication for sudo taken care of by Solokey, we can separate permissions for privileged data access, by creating additional user accounts.&#xA;One use case for this can be to control access to command line programs that store sensitive API tokens, via sudo.&#xA;Index DigitalOcean app user (doctl) </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Config</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/config/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/config/index.html</guid>
      <description> Index Sway Firefox Toolbox Emacs SSH </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KVM / libvirt</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/kvm-libvirt/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/kvm-libvirt/index.html</guid>
      <description>Idealistically, the introduction declared a “No Sworkstations” rule (No Server-Workstations). Pragmatically, you can bend this rule a bit, by hosting some development servers inside of virtual machines (VM). Hosting VMs on your workstation is convenient for having a portable lab environment. By using virtual machines for all services, we get to maintain our core distinction between the roles of workstation and server.&#xA;This paradigm is considerably more adhoc than a proper hypervisor operating system like Proxmox.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>