<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux Workstation :: book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/index.html</link>
    <description>This book describes how I setup a Linux Workstation (on a personal Desktop or Laptop computer).&#xA;Index Introduction Fedora Sway Atomic Requirements Install Linux (Fedora Atomic) Config Sway Firefox Toolbox Emacs SSH </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/introduction/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/introduction/index.html</guid>
      <description>A Linux Workstation is a single user computer that you use as your primary interface for computing, especially for “work” purposes. At a bare minimum, a workstation includes a keyboard to type on, and a display to display things on. Historically, there has been a hardware distinction between a personal computer (PC) and a Unix workstation, but ever since the introduction of Linux, the difference in hardware doesn’t really exist anymore, and any computing device can become a workstation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install Linux (Fedora Atomic)</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/install/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/install/index.html</guid>
      <description>Create USB installation media Download the Fedora Sway Atomic iso image. Assuming you are temporarily using another Linux workstation, write the .iso image to a USB drive:&#xA;[bash]: Run this on your workstation: dd if=Fedora-Sericea-ostree-x86_64-40-1.14.iso \ of=/dev/sdX bs=10M status=progress conv=sync Info Replace /dev/sdX with your device name, and double check the .iso filename, it may have changed.&#xA;Boot the target workstation computer using the USB drive. You will boot into the Anaconda install wizard.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Config</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/config/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/config/index.html</guid>
      <description> Index Sway Firefox Toolbox Emacs SSH </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>