<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Install apps :: book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/install-web-services/index.html</link>
    <description> You may install any of the apps bundled with d.rymcg.tech or you can create your own. Included in this chapter are instructions for only a subset of the available apps.&#xA;Index Immich SFTP (and Thttpd) Homepage Yourls </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/install-web-services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Immich</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/install-web-services/immich/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/install-web-services/immich/index.html</guid>
      <description>Immich is an open-source self-hosted photo and video management solution. Configure Immich Run this on the Raspberry Pi pi make immich config (stdout) IMMICH_TRAEFIK_HOST: Enter the Immich domain name (e.g., immich.example.com) : immich.pi.example.com ? Do you want to enable sentry authorization in front of this app (effectively making the entire site private)? &gt; No Yes, with HTTP Basic Authentication Yes, with Oauth2 Yes, with Mutual TLS (mTLS) ? Select the hardware acceleration to use for machine learning &gt; CPU .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SFTP (and Thttpd)</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/install-web-services/sftp/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/install-web-services/sftp/index.html</guid>
      <description>SFTP (SSH File Transfer Protocol) is a standard and secure method of transferring files. There are clients available for all platforms. You can configure an SFTP server to send and receive files directly with your Docker volumes.&#xA;Install a demo web server (thttpd) Thttpd is a tiny static HTTP server for hosting websites. It will be used for demonstration purposes in showing the effect of transferring files directly into its volume, via SFTP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homepage</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/install-web-services/homepage/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/install-web-services/homepage/index.html</guid>
      <description>Homepage is a customizable dashboard for all of your self-hosted apps and services.&#xA;Configure Homepage Run this on your Raspberry Pi pi make homepage config You need to configure two sub-domains, one for homepage itself, and one for its webhooks:&#xA;(stdout) HOMEPAGE_TRAEFIK_HOST: Enter the homepage domain name (eg. homepage.example.com) : homepage.pi.example.com HOMEPAGE_WEBHOOK_HOST: Enter the separate webhook domain name (eg. homepage-webhook.example.com) : homepage-webhook.pi.example.com You can enable automatic service discovery by enabling the optional Docker support (recommended):</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yourls</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/install-web-services/yourls/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/install-web-services/yourls/index.html</guid>
      <description>Yourls is a URL shortener. Configure Yourls Run this on the Raspberry Pi pi make yourls config Follow the prompts to configure the domain name and admin user authentication. (stdout) YOURLS_TRAEFIK_HOST: Enter the YOURLS domain name (e.g., yourls.example.com) : yourls.pi.example.com ? Do you want to enable sentry authorization in front of this app (effectively making the entire site private)? &gt; No Yes, with HTTP Basic Authentication Yes, with Oauth2 Yes, with Mutual TLS (mTLS) YOURLS_USER: Enter the admin username for your YOURLS instance : admin YOURLS_PASS: Enter the password for &#39;admin&#39; : 528e0e36fc170 Choose your own a secure passphrase!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>