<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Setup your workstation :: book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/index.html</link>
    <description>You should dedicate the use a physical or virtual Linux machine to be used as your workstation. A single workstation can manage several remote Docker contexts.&#xA;Follow the Linux Workstation book for details on basic workstation setup.&#xA;All the commands in this chapter assume you are using the standard Bash shell.&#xA;Index Install Docker client tools Install d.rymcg.tech tools </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Install Docker client tools</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-docker-command-line-tools/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-docker-command-line-tools/index.html</guid>
      <description>You need to install Docker Engine (not Docker Desktop!) on your workstation.&#xA;You will completely disable the Docker daemon on your workstation, you’re only installing Docker Engine for its client tools (eg. the docker command).&#xA;Various ways to install Docker Engine Install from upstream Docker package repository The Docker organization provides several up-to-date packages for various Linux distributions:&#xA;Fedora Debian Ubuntu Try your system package manager Some Linux distributions have decent packages for up-to-date Docker versions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install d.rymcg.tech tools</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-d-rymcg-tech/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-d-rymcg-tech/index.html</guid>
      <description>Install d.rymcg.tech and its dependencies on your workstation.&#xA;Install dependent packages If you run Fedora workstations, run this as root sudo dnf install bash gettext openssl git xdg-utils jq sshfs curl \ inotify-tools httpd-tools make wireguard-tools If you run Debian/Ubuntu workstations, run this as root sudo apt-get install bash build-essential gettext git openssl \ apache2-utils xdg-utils jq sshfs wireguard curl \ inotify-tools If you run Arch Linux workstations, run this as root sudo pacman -S bash base-devel gettext git openssl apache xdg-utils \ jq sshfs wireguard-tools curl inotify-tools Clone d.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>