<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Setup your workstation :: book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/index.html</link>
    <description>You should dedicate the use a physical or virtual Linux machine to be used as your workstation. A single workstation can manage several remote Docker contexts.&#xA;Follow the Linux Workstation book for details on basic workstation setup.&#xA;All the commands in this chapter assume you are using the standard Bash shell.&#xA;Index Install Docker client tools Install d.rymcg.tech tools Create SSH config and Docker Context Install Docker on your remote host Main config for d.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Install Docker client tools</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-docker-command-line-tools/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-docker-command-line-tools/index.html</guid>
      <description>You need to install Docker Engine (not Docker Desktop!) on your workstation.&#xA;You will completely disable the Docker daemon on your workstation, you’re only installing Docker Engine for its client tools (eg. the docker command).&#xA;Various ways to install Docker Engine Try your system package manager Some Linux distributions have decent packages for up-to-date Docker versions. Some other distributions lag behind by several versions, or may even introduce non-standard changes of their own.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install d.rymcg.tech tools</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-d-rymcg-tech/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-d-rymcg-tech/index.html</guid>
      <description>Install d.rymcg.tech and its dependencies on your workstation.&#xA;Install dependent packages If you run Fedora workstations, run this as root dnf install bash gettext openssl git xdg-utils jq sshfs curl \ inotify-tools httpd-tools make wireguard-tools If you run Debian/Ubuntu workstations, run this as root apt-get install bash build-essential gettext git openssl \ apache2-utils xdg-utils jq sshfs wireguard curl \ inotify-tools If you run Arch Linux workstations, run this as root pacman -S bash base-devel gettext git openssl apache xdg-utils \ jq sshfs wireguard-tools curl inotify-tools Clone d.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create SSH config and Docker Context</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/ssh-config-and-docker-context/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/ssh-config-and-docker-context/index.html</guid>
      <description>To remotely control your Docker host from your workstation, you need two additional configs:&#xA;SSH Host config in ~/.ssh/config. Docker Context config via docker context create .... Both of these can be created automatically by running:&#xA;[bash]: Run this on your workstation: d context new This will prompt you if you really want to proceed:&#xA;(stdout) ? This command can help create a new SSH config and Docker context. Proceed? (Y/n) y You can choose to create a new SSH config, or use an existing one:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install Docker on your remote host</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-docker-on-remote-host/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-docker-on-remote-host/index.html</guid>
      <description>The base Debian image only has a few basic commands preinstalled. You must now install the Docker packages and enable the service:&#xA;Choose the active Docker context d context [bash]: Run this on your workstation: d install-docker Tip d install-docker will install Docker on the remote VPS, according to your active docker context.&#xA;Test that the context works from your workstation [bash]: Run this on your workstation: docker run hello-world [bash]: Run this on your workstation: docker ps </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Main config for d.rymcg.tech</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/main-config-for-d.rymcg/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/main-config-for-d.rymcg/index.html</guid>
      <description>Select your active Docker context [bash]: Run this on your workstation: d context Each Docker context has a separate config file (.env_{CONTEXT}), stored in the root d.rymcg.tech directory (~/git/vendor/enigmacurry/d.rymcg.tech), so you must actively select your current context before you can configure it.&#xA;Configure d.rymcg.tech for the current Docker context [bash]: Run this on your workstation: d make - config This will create a config file for your current Docker context, and name it .</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>