<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Setup your workstation on book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Setup your workstation on book.rymcg.tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Install Docker client tools</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-docker-command-line-tools/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-docker-command-line-tools/index.html</guid>
      <description>You need to install Docker Engine on your workstation
Try your system package manager Some Linux distributions have decent packages for up-to-date Docker versions. Some other distributions lag behind by several versions, or may even introduce non-standard changes of their own. Your mileage may vary with different operating systems.
If you&amp;rsquo;re on Arch Linux, this is known to be a good configuration:
Run this on your Arch Linux workstations: :: sudo pacman -S docker docker-compose docker-buildx Use the generic Docker installer If your Linux distribution doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide a Docker package, or you&amp;rsquo;ve decided its not good for your situation, you may be better off by running the generic installer script from the upstream Docker organization:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install d.rymcg.tech tools</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-d-rymcg-tech/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-d-rymcg-tech/index.html</guid>
      <description>Install d.rymcg.tech and its dependencies on your workstation.
Install dependent packages If you run Fedora workstations, run this as root :: dnf install bash gettext openssl git xdg-utils jq sshfs curl \ inotify-tools httpd-tools make wireguard-tools If you run Debian/Ubuntu workstations, run this as root :: apt-get install bash build-essential gettext git openssl \ apache2-utils xdg-utils jq sshfs wireguard curl \ inotify-tools If you run Arch Linux workstations, run this as root :: pacman -S bash base-devel gettext git openssl apache xdg-utils \ jq sshfs wireguard-tools curl inotify-tools Clone d.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create SSH config and Docker Context</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/ssh-config-and-docker-context/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/ssh-config-and-docker-context/index.html</guid>
      <description>To remotely control your Docker host from your workstation, you need two additional configs:
SSH Host config in ~/.ssh/config. Docker Context config via docker context create .... Both of these can be created automatically by running:
Run this on your Workstation Bash shell :: d context new This will prompt you if you really want to proceed:
(stdout) ? This command can help create a new SSH config and Docker context.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install Docker on your remote host</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-docker-on-remote-host/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-docker-on-remote-host/index.html</guid>
      <description>The base Debian image only has a few basic commands preinstalled. You must now install the Docker packages and enable the service:
Run this on your Workstation Bash shell :: d install-docker Tip d install-docker will install Docker on the remote VPS, according to your current docker context.
Test that the context works from your workstation Run this on your Workstation Bash shell :: docker run hello-world Run this on your Workstation Bash shell :: docker ps </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Main config for d.rymcg.tech</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/main-config-for-d.rymcg/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/main-config-for-d.rymcg/index.html</guid>
      <description>Select your active Docker context Run this on your Workstation Bash shell :: d context Each Docker context has a separate config file (.env_{CONTEXT}), stored in the root d.rymcg.tech directory (~/git/vendor/enigmacurry/d.rymcg.tech), so you must actively select your current context before you can configure it.
Configure d.rymcg.tech for the current Docker context Run this on your Workstation Bash shell :: d make - config This will create a config file for your current Docker context, and name it .</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>