<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Setup your workstation on book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Setup your workstation on book.rymcg.tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Install d.rymcg.tech tools</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-d-rymcg-tech/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-d-rymcg-tech/index.html</guid>
      <description>Install d.rymcg.tech and its dependencies on your workstation.
Install dependencies Run this on your Fedora workstations as root :: dnf install bash gettext openssl git xdg-utils jq sshfs curl \ inotify-tools httpd-tools make wireguard-tools Run this on your Debian workstations as root :: apt-get install bash build-essential gettext git openssl \ apache2-utils xdg-utils jq sshfs wireguard curl \ inotify-tools Run this on your Arch Linux workstations as root :: pacman -S bash base-devel gettext git openssl apache xdg-utils \ jq sshfs wireguard-tools curl inotify-tools Clone d.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Main config for d.rymcg.tech</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/main-config-for-d.rymcg/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/main-config-for-d.rymcg/index.html</guid>
      <description>Select your active Docker context Run this on your Workstation Bash shell :: d context You can view, and select from, all of the configured Docker contexts on your workstation:
(stdout) ? Select the Docker context to use &gt; deb default step-ca test-tmp [↑↓ to move, enter to select, type to filter, ESC to cancel] Each Docker context has a separate config file (.env_{CONTEXT}), stored in the root d.rymcg.tech directory (~/git/vendor/enigmacurry/d.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install Traefik Proxy</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-traefik-proxy/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/install-traefik-proxy/index.html</guid>
      <description>Configure Traefik Proxy Run on your workstation:
Run this on your Workstation Bash shell :: d make traefik config The configuration for Traefik is driven by a text wizard menu system.
(stdout) ? Traefik config main menu: &gt; Create system user on Docker host Configure entrypoints (including dashboard) Configure Certificate Authorities (CA) Configure ACME (Let&#39;s Encrypt or Step-CA) Configure TLS certificates and domains (make certs) Configure middleware (including auth) v Configure error page template [↑↓ to move, enter to select, type to filter, ESC to cancel] Use your arrow keys to select a menu item and press the Enter key.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>