<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Self-hosting Docker with d.rymcg.tech :: book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/index.html</link>
    <description>This book describes how to get started with self-hosting your own Docker server, using the tools provided by d.rymcg.tech.&#xA;d.rymcg.tech Chat with us on Matrix Index Introduction Required Infrastructure Register a domain name Setup public DNS service Create a public server (VPS) Create a private server (libvirt VM) Setup your workstation Install Docker client tools Install d.rymcg.tech tools Setup Docker context Create SSH config and Docker context Install Docker on your remote host Setup d.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/introduction/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/introduction/index.html</guid>
      <description>What is self-hosting? Self-hosting is the practice of hosting network applications (web / internet / LAN / etc), using your own server hardware, or at least on virtual machines that you fundamentally control (ie. you have root access). As a preparedness skill, the self-hoster prioritizes the use of open source software, as it becomes an inalienable toolset to bootstrap infrastructure in the wilderness.&#xA;You can apply self-hosting a little bit, or a lot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Required Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/required-infrastructure/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/required-infrastructure/index.html</guid>
      <description>A public internet Docker server needs several resources that you need to procure :&#xA;A domain name registrar (eg. Gandi.net). A domain name server (eg. DigitalOcean DNS). A Linux compute platform on which to install Docker (eg. DigitalOcean Droplet). An internet network connection (eg. DigitalOcean network). Index Register a domain name Setup public DNS service Create a public server (VPS) Create a private server (libvirt VM) </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setup your workstation</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/index.html</guid>
      <description>You should dedicate the use a physical or virtual Linux machine to be used as your workstation. A single workstation can manage several remote Docker contexts.&#xA;Follow the Linux Workstation book for details on basic workstation setup.&#xA;All the commands in this chapter assume you are using the standard Bash shell.&#xA;Index Install Docker client tools Install d.rymcg.tech tools </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setup Docker context</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/docker-context/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/docker-context/index.html</guid>
      <description>To remotely control a Docker server, you need to create a Docker context on your workstation, which is basically the SSH connection information to setup the docker socket connection.&#xA;Index Create SSH config and Docker context Install Docker on your remote host Setup d.rymcg.tech per Docker context </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traefik Proxy</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/index.html</guid>
      <description>Traefik Proxy (Traefik) is a core service, an application gateway, for all of the service containers installed on your Docker host. Traefik is an advanced software router: it can serve hundreds of deployed application containers (routes) at the same time. Traefik has a configuration provider that operates by discovery, so that when it is installed on a Docker host, it can automatically configure itself based upon the runtime settings of each individual application it finds.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whoami</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/whoami/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/whoami/index.html</guid>
      <description>Whoami is a very simple application, but you can learn a lot from it. After you install Traefik, whoami should be the very next application that you install. It can help you test whether or not your Traefik installation is functioning properly.&#xA;You should study the configuration of whoami, as it is used as a template for all the other apps provided by d.rymcg.tech. Whoami can be a good base template for creating your own d.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Step-CA</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/step-ca/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/step-ca/index.html</guid>
      <description>Step-CA is a secure, online, self-hosted Certificate Authority (CA). Its purpose is to issue (sign) X.509 (TLS) certificates, and to securely store the private key for the root CA. It can issue certificates manually using the step-cli tool, or Traefik can request them automatically via the ACME protocol.&#xA;Index Install Step-CA Create Certificates Configure TLS clients Change Root CA Passphrase ACME Mutual TLS </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>