<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Self-hosting Docker with d.rymcg.tech on book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self-hosting Docker with d.rymcg.tech on book.rymcg.tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/introduction/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/introduction/index.html</guid>
      <description>What is self-hosting? Self-hosting is the practice of hosting network applications (web / internet / LAN / etc), using your own server hardware, or at least on virtual machines that you fundamentally control (ie. you have root access). As a preparedness skill, the self-hoster prioritizes the use of open source software, as it becomes an inalienable toolset to bootstrap infrastructure in the wilderness.
You can apply self-hosting a little bit, or a lot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a public Docker server</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/public-docker-server/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/public-docker-server/index.html</guid>
      <description>This section will guide you to create your own public Docker server, using a DigitalOcean droplet as an example. In a similar fashion, you can install Docker on any cloud provider, or dedicated host that you prefer.
Choosing a VPS provider One of the most basic units of cloud computing is the Virtual Private Server (VPS). A VPS is a (Linux) virtual machine that is provisioned by a cloud service, and you are given root access to fully administer it, to install whatever you want on it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Domain Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/domain-infrastructure/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/domain-infrastructure/index.html</guid>
      <description>A public internet Docker server needs several resources that you need to procure :
A Linux compute platform on which to install Docker (eg. DigitalOcean Droplet). An internet network connection (eg. DigitalOcean network). A domain name registrar (eg. Gandi.net). A domain name server (eg. DigitalOcean DNS). Index Register a domain name Setup public DNS service </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setup your workstation</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/index.html</guid>
      <description>Index Install d.rymcg.tech tools Create SSH config and Docker Context Main config for d.rymcg.tech </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install Traefik Proxy</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/install-traefik-proxy/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/install-traefik-proxy/index.html</guid>
      <description>Configure Traefik Proxy Run on your workstation:
Run this on your Workstation Bash shell :: d make traefik config This creates a config for Traefik on your active Docker context. The configuration is driven by a text wizard menu system.
Once complete, it will have created and configured your .env_{CONTEXT} file for you.
(stdout) ? Traefik config main menu: &gt; Create system user on Docker host Configure entrypoints (including dashboard) Configure Certificate Authorities (CA) Configure ACME (Let&#39;s Encrypt or Step-CA) Configure TLS certificates and domains (make certs) Configure middleware (including auth) v Configure error page template [↑↓ to move, enter to select, type to filter, ESC to cancel] Use your arrow keys to select a menu item and press the Enter key.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>