<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Self-hosting Docker with d.rymcg.tech on org.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://org.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self-hosting Docker with d.rymcg.tech on org.rymcg.tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://org.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://org.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/introduction/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://org.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/introduction/index.html</guid>
      <description>What is self-hosting? Self-hosting is described on Wikipedia as the following:
Self-hosting is the practice of running and maintaining a website or service using a private web server, instead of using a service outside of someone&amp;rsquo;s own control. Self-hosting allows users to have more control over their data, privacy, and computing infrastructure, as well as potentially saving costs and improving skills.
You can apply self-hosting a little bit, or a lot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Register a domain name</title>
      <link>https://org.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/register-a-domain-name/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://org.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/register-a-domain-name/index.html</guid>
      <description>To host a web service, one of the first things you will need is to register your domain name. This will be the domain name used for all your service links, and it is what your users will need to type into their browsers to visit your pages.
Domain names a scarce resource. Because of their scarcity, you must pay for your domain registrations, doing so in 1 year increments. If domains were free, all the good ones would be taken by now, but because they cost money, there are still some good enough ones left to be had.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setup public DNS</title>
      <link>https://org.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/setup-dns/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://org.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/setup-dns/index.html</guid>
      <description>A DNS server maps your domain (and subdomain) names to the various IP addresses of your servers. DNS is required for your users to be able to type your domain name prod.example.com and have it resolve to the IP address that is required to contact your Docker server.
Now that you have registered a domain name, you need to tell your registrar where your DNS server is. Usually you will use the DNS server that your cloud provider gives you, but you may choose any DNS provider you like.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a Docker server</title>
      <link>https://org.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/docker-server/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://org.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/docker-server/index.html</guid>
      <description>The next three chapters will guide you to install Docker, for three different server scenarios:
A production/staging Docker server on the public Internet (eg. DigitalOcean or any other VPS cloud provider). A production/staging Docker server on a private LAN. A development Docker server in a local VM. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a public Docker server</title>
      <link>https://org.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/public-docker-server/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://org.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/public-docker-server/index.html</guid>
      <description>This section will guide you to create your own public Docker server as a DigitalOcean droplet, however you may also install Docker on any cloud provider or dedicated host that you prefer.
Choosing a VPS provider One of the most basic units of cloud computing is the Virtual Private Server (VPS). A VPS is a virtual machine that is provisioned by a cloud service, that you are given full adminstrative control of.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a private Docker Server for a LAN</title>
      <link>https://org.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/private-docker-server/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://org.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/private-docker-server/index.html</guid>
      <description>Create a VM
Setup private DNS If you chose a fake domain, you can set the DNS record on your local DNS server. Generally, most LANs already have a local DNS server install on a home router. You can add your records there. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a DNS server, you can install dnsmasq. dnsmasq can act as DNS and/or DHCP servers for your LAN.
A dnsmasq entry for the wildcard records would look like this (in dnsmasq.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a development Docker Server VM</title>
      <link>https://org.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/development-docker-server-vm/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://org.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/development-docker-server-vm/index.html</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>