<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Self-hosting Docker with d.rymcg.tech on book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self-hosting Docker with d.rymcg.tech on book.rymcg.tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/introduction/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/introduction/index.html</guid>
      <description>What is self-hosting? Self-hosting is the practice of hosting network applications (web / internet / LAN / etc), using your own server hardware, or at least on virtual machines that you fundamentally control (ie. you have root access). As a preparedness skill, the self-hoster prioritizes the use of open source software, as it becomes an inalienable toolset to bootstrap infrastructure in the wilderness.
You can apply self-hosting a little bit, or a lot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Required Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/required-infrastructure/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/required-infrastructure/index.html</guid>
      <description>A public internet Docker server needs several resources that you need to procure :
A domain name registrar (eg. Gandi.net). A domain name server (eg. DigitalOcean DNS). A Linux compute platform on which to install Docker (eg. DigitalOcean Droplet). An internet network connection (eg. DigitalOcean network). Index Register a domain name Setup public DNS service Create a public server (VPS) </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setup your workstation</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/workstation/index.html</guid>
      <description>You should dedicate the use a physical or virtual Linux machine to be used as your workstation. A single workstation can manage several remote Docker contexts.
Follow the Linux Workstation book for details on basic workstation setup.
All the commands in this chapter assume you are using the standard Bash shell.
Index Install Docker client tools Install d.rymcg.tech tools Create SSH config and Docker Context Install Docker on your remote host Main config for d.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install Traefik Proxy</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/install-traefik-proxy/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/install-traefik-proxy/index.html</guid>
      <description>Traefik Proxy is a core service that acts as a gateway for all of the other applications installed on your Docker host. Everything that is served behind Traefik Proxy can take advantage of automatic TLS certificates (ACME), perform user authentication (mTLS, OAuth2, HTTP Basic), apply sentry authorization (user account filtering), and IP address filtering middlewares. Based on all of this criteria, Traefik Proxy ultimately decides whether to route incoming requests to the backend service containers, or to block it and return an error.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whoami</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/whoami/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/whoami/index.html</guid>
      <description>Whoami is a very simple application, but you can learn a lot from it. After Traefik, it should be the very first application that you install. It can help you test whether or not your Traefik installation is functioning properly.
Later on, you will come to realize how similar all of the other applications provided by d.rymcg.tech are to whoami, by the common methods that they are configured and managed. You should study the configuration of whoami.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>