<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction :: book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/introduction/index.html</link>
    <description>A Linux Workstation is a single user computer that you use as your primary interface for computing, especially for “work” purposes. At a bare minimum, a workstation includes a keyboard and a display (although a workstation could also be a VPS that you SSH into, this book will focus on physical workstations).&#xA;Historically, there has been a hardware distinction between a personal computer (PC) and a Unix workstation, but ever since the introduction of Linux, the difference in hardware doesn’t really matter anymore, and any computing device can become a workstation.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fedora Sway Atomic</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/introduction/fedora-sway-atomic/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/introduction/fedora-sway-atomic/index.html</guid>
      <description>I have tried a great many different Linux distributions over the years, but I have recently settled on using Fedora Sway Atomic for my desktop and laptop workstations.&#xA;Sway is a minimal tiling window manager for Wayland. It is ideal for efficient keyboard centric development and for getting out of your way.&#xA;The “Atomic” part refers to rpm-ostree, which was originally used by the CoreOS team to build an operating system that is built entirely to support containers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Requirements</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/introduction/requirements/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/introduction/requirements/index.html</guid>
      <description>You will need the following hardware:&#xA;An x86_64 desktop or laptop computer to install to. A USB drive for copying the .iso installer to. A solokey or other FIDO2 compatible hardware authentication key. (This is optional, but highly recommended for storing secure shell keys, PGP keys, and logging into websites with Webauthn.) </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>