<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Traefik Proxy :: book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/index.html</link>
    <description>Traefik Proxy (Traefik) is a core service, an application gateway, for all of the service containers installed on your Docker host. Traefik is an advanced software router: it can serve hundreds of deployed application containers (routes) at the same time. Traefik has a configuration provider that operates by discovery, so that when it is installed on a Docker host, it can automatically configure itself based upon the runtime settings of each individual application it finds.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Traefik Quickstart (public VPS)</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/vps-quickstart/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/vps-quickstart/index.html</guid>
      <description>Before we get too deep into Traefik configuration, if you just want to setup a public VPS, follow these instructions as a quickstart tutorial: Choose your active Docker context [bash]: Run this on your workstation: d context Configure Traefik [bash]: Run this on your workstation: d make traefik config The configuration is driven by a text wizard menu system. (stdout) ? Traefik config main menu: &gt; Create system user on Docker host Configure entrypoints (including dashboard) Configure Certificate Authorities (CA) Configure ACME (Let&#39;s Encrypt or Step-CA) Configure TLS certificates and domains (make certs) Configure middleware (including auth) v Configure error page template [↑↓ to move, enter to select, type to filter, ESC to cancel] Use your arrow keys to select only the menu items this tutorial talks about, and press the Enter key.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>