<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Set up sentry Droplet :: book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-cloud-sentry/index.html</link>
    <description> Index Launch DigitalOcean droplet Configure the sentry context on the Pi Configure d.rymcg.tech for the sentry </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-cloud-sentry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Launch DigitalOcean droplet</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-cloud-sentry/launch-digitalocean-droplet/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-cloud-sentry/launch-digitalocean-droplet/index.html</guid>
      <description>Set up your SSH key on DigitalOcean How to do this in the DigitalOcean cloud console Login to the DigitalOcean cloud console. Click Settings in the menu. Click on the Security tab. Click on the Add SSH Key button. Paste the public SSH key of the pi user into the box. (copy the contents of ~/.ssh/id_ed25519.pub from the Raspberry Pi.) Enter a key name e.g., pi@pi.example.com. Finish adding the key, click Add SSH Key.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure the sentry context on the Pi</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-cloud-sentry/set-up-docker-context/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-cloud-sentry/set-up-docker-context/index.html</guid>
      <description>You now need to be able to control the droplet’s root user from the Raspberry Pi’s pi user. Create a new SSH config entry for the sentry (replace sentry.example.com with your own droplet’s DNS name):&#xA;Append to the SSH config on the Pi Run this on the Raspberry Pi cat &lt;&lt;EOF &gt;&gt; ~/.ssh/config Host sentry User root Hostname sentry.example.com ControlMaster auto ControlPersist yes ControlPath /tmp/ssh-%u-%r@%h:%p EOF Tip The Hostname value should point to the same name you created the DNS entry for the sentry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Configure d.rymcg.tech for the sentry</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-cloud-sentry/configure-d-rymcg-tech-for-sentry/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/set-up-cloud-sentry/configure-d-rymcg-tech-for-sentry/index.html</guid>
      <description>Run the main config The main config must be run for each new context you create: Run this on the Raspberry Pi sentry config (stdout) &gt; This will make a configuration for the current docker context (sentry). Proceed? Yes ROOT_DOMAIN: Enter the root domain for this context (e.g., d.example.com) : sentry.example.com Install Traefik This is a very similar process as when you installed Traefik on the Raspberry Pi: Run this on the Raspberry Pi sentry make traefik config (stdout) ?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>