<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maintainence :: book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/maintainence/index.html</link>
    <description> Index Backup Upgrade Troubleshooting </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/maintainence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Backup</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/maintainence/backup/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/maintainence/backup/index.html</guid>
      <description>Native systems are harder to backup than virtual systems, thats just the way it goes. With VMs, your hypervisor usually has a builtin backup feature which pauses the machine, makes a snapshot, resumes the machine, and continues backing up the snapshot in the background. If you have the luxury of running your server as a VM (e.g., Proxmox PVE), it makes backups so much easier.&#xA;However in this book we are dealing with a physical Raspberry Pi, not a virtual machine, so backup must be managed another way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/maintainence/upgrade/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/maintainence/upgrade/index.html</guid>
      <description>Upgrade Raspberry Pi OS Run this on your Raspberry Pi sudo apt update sudo apt full-upgrade sudo reboot Upgrade container images Each application is configured via its own .env_{CONTEXT}_{INSTANCE} file in the project folder of each app.&#xA;The version of the app is usually controlled via an environment variable named PROJECT_IMAGE or PROJECT_VERSION. For some apps, this will be labeled as latest so that it always installs the latest version, while others are locked to a specific know working version.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/maintainence/troubleshooting/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/portable-docker/maintainence/troubleshooting/index.html</guid>
      <description>Monitor kernel logs During the first day or so of setting this machine up, it is recommended to actively monitor the kernel logs, checking for errors.&#xA;[bash]: Run this on your workstation: ## Just leave this running in a separate terminal as you keep working.. sudo dmesg -w Disable power saving on NVME storage How to disable power saving on the NVME drive Out of two identical kits, I encountered one error in the kernel log on one machine but not on the other, so you may or may not run into this error:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>