<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publishing with org-mode :: book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/publishing-with-org-mode/index.html</link>
    <description>This book describes how this site is written, in Org-mode, with ox-hugo, and bits of Literate Programming.&#xA;Index Dependencies Building locally Publishing with GitHub pages Publishing with SFTP Using Org-mode and Emacs Navigating Org-mode files Editing Org-mode files Example Org / Hugo content Example Org Blocks Example Shortcodes Example of a deeply … Nested … Sub-chapter 1 Sub-chapter 2 Sub-chapter 3 </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/publishing-with-org-mode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dependencies</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/publishing-with-org-mode/dependencies/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/publishing-with-org-mode/dependencies/index.html</guid>
      <description>This site is built with:&#xA;Emacs Org-mode Ox-hugo Hugo (extended edition) GitHub actions (also compatible with Gitea actions) The GitHub/Gitea actions file includes all its dependencies declaratively.&#xA;To build locally, you must install Emacs (29+), and hugo (v0.120+), using your package manager, or by downloading directly from their respective project pages. Please be aware that hugo has two editions: standard and extended, and this build requires the extended edition (TODO: verify this - I had some problems before - but maybe they are resolved - I am still using the extended edition for now).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building locally</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/publishing-with-org-mode/building-locally/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/publishing-with-org-mode/building-locally/index.html</guid>
      <description>Change into the directory where you cloned the source:&#xA;[bash]: Run this on your workstation: cd ~/git/vendor/enigmacurry/org Run the install method to download the theme:&#xA;[bash]: Run this on your workstation: ## This just downloads/installs the theme: make install Build the site:&#xA;[bash]: Run this on your workstation: ## This builds the entire static site into the public/ directory: make build Run the development server:&#xA;[bash]: Run this on your workstation: ## This builds the entire site, and then runs the live reload server: make serve </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publishing with GitHub pages</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/publishing-with-org-mode/publish-with-github-pages/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/publishing-with-org-mode/publish-with-github-pages/index.html</guid>
      <description>This site is automatically published to GitHub Pages via the included action file: .github/workflows/deploy.yaml. You can fork the repository and enable the action to run on your behalf and publish to your own site automatically, whenever you run git push.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publishing with SFTP</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/publishing-with-org-mode/publish-with-sftp/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/publishing-with-org-mode/publish-with-sftp/index.html</guid>
      <description>If you don’t want to use GitHub pages, you can alternatively publish to any webserver via SFTP.&#xA;To do so, you must install Rclone.&#xA;For example, on Fedora:&#xA;[bash]: Run this on your workstation: ## On Fedora atomic, make sure to do this in a toolbox container: sudo dnf install rclone Once installed, you need to configure the remote SFTP server you want to publish to:&#xA;[bash]: Run this on your workstation: rclone config Follow the prompts to setup your SFTP remote, or you can see the example SFTP documentation for doing this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Org-mode and Emacs</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/publishing-with-org-mode/org-mode-emacs/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/publishing-with-org-mode/org-mode-emacs/index.html</guid>
      <description>Here are some tips on using Org-mode and Emacs.&#xA;Read the Org manual Many of these tips are found in the Org Manual.&#xA;Index Navigating Org-mode files Editing Org-mode files </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Example Org / Hugo content</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/publishing-with-org-mode/examples/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/publishing-with-org-mode/examples/index.html</guid>
      <description>This chapter serves as an example of various shortcodes/markup for Ox-Hugo and the Hugo Relearn theme.&#xA;This chapter is broken into several sub-chapters to discuss the various Hugo related features.&#xA;Index Example Org Blocks Example Shortcodes Example of a deeply … Nested … Sub-chapter 1 Sub-chapter 2 Sub-chapter 3 </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>