<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Config :: book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/config/index.html</link>
    <description> Index Sway Firefox Toolbox Emacs SSH </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/config/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sway</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/config/sway/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/config/sway/index.html</guid>
      <description>Sway is a reimagining of i3wm (X11), rewritten for Wayland. Sway (like i3wm) is a keyboard centric tiling window manager. Although not a source fork of i3wm, the configuration and user interface of Sway is almost identical to that of i3wm.&#xA;Sway Config The Fedora Atomic Sway edition includes a default configuration for Sway. It’s pretty nice out of the box, and so if you like it, you can just use it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firefox</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/config/firefox/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/config/firefox/index.html</guid>
      <description>Fedora Atomic ships with the Firefox browser preinstalled. This section describes how I like to set it up.&#xA;Remove clutter Remove Firefox View, right click the upper left icon and select Remove from toolbar. Remove existing bookmarks from bookmark bar, right click each one and select Delete. Remove Pocket, right click the pocket icon in the upper right toolbar, select Remove from toolbar Remove Firefox Account icon, select Remove from toolbar Firefox Settings Go into the Firefox settings: click the “hamburger” menu in the top right toolbar.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toolbox</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/config/toolbox/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/config/toolbox/index.html</guid>
      <description>Toolbox is an integral part of Fedora Atomic, being one of the main methods of installing software, it lets you run your applications inside of Podman containers. Toolbox can actually be used on any Linux system that is capable of running Podman, but is especially useful on Atomic hosts. Toolbox is more tightly integrated with your host OS than Docker or Podman containers normally are. Toolbox containers share the same /home directory with the host (bind mounted), and they live in the same network and process namespace as the host (ie.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emacs</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/config/emacs-on-fedora/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/config/emacs-on-fedora/index.html</guid>
      <description>Emacs is my long time favorite code editor (IDE) and for writing documentation (including this book).&#xA;Install Emacs Because Sway runs on Wayland, you’ll want to install the Wayland (pgtk) version of Emacs. In Fedora 40 onwards, the Wayland (pgtk) version is already the default. For Fedora 39, you can use this COPR (a COPR is to Fedora what PPA is to Ubuntu and what AUR is to Arch Linux), which includes a custom build for Wayland (pgtk).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSH</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/config/ssh/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/linux-workstation/config/ssh/index.html</guid>
      <description>SSH (secure shell) is a secure networking tool used between a client and a server. Using an encrypted network protocol, it can be used to securely login to a server remotely, as well as for more advanded networking scenarios. Typical use cases for SSH include:&#xA;Access to a server’s console shell, remotely. Transfer files between the server and client (using rsync, scp, or sftp). Create network tunnels to access private servers, in both directions, either on the server, or on the client.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>