<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Traefik Scenarios :: book.rymcg.tech</title>
    <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/scenarios/index.html</link>
    <description>This section will discuss deploying Traefik in a variety of scenarios. Each scenario will build upon the next, so you might consider following them in order, but you can also skip straight to the one you want, as each set of instructions is self-contained.&#xA;Index Minimal Traefik Let&#39;s Encrypt TLS challenge Let&#39;s Encrypt DNS challenge Step-CA TLS challenge Step-CA DNS challenge Wireguard layer 7 proxy Wireguard layer 7 client Wireguard layer 4 client </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/scenarios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Minimal Traefik</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/scenarios/minimal/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/scenarios/minimal/index.html</guid>
      <description>This scenario covers the bare minimum Traefik configuration. All optional configuration will be skipped. This is the minimum config to serve a website on port 443, but only with temporary self self-signed TLS certificates (“Traefik Default”).&#xA;Tip This scenario is good for testing, but not for secure public access.&#xA;Choose your active Docker context [bash]: Run this on your workstation: d context Configure Traefik Warning If you want to reset the existing config back to the defaults, run:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Encrypt TLS challenge</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/scenarios/vps-lets-encrypt-tls-challenge/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/scenarios/vps-lets-encrypt-tls-challenge/index.html</guid>
      <description>This scenario covers a basic Traefik configuration for a public server (VPS). This uses Let’s Encrypt to sign TLS certificates, which are valid for use in most web browsers. This scenario will use the TLS-ALPN-01 challenge type.&#xA;Warning This scenario is only good for public websites and services. For (semi-)private servers, that you don’t really want the world to know about yet, you should avoid this and use the DNS-01 challenge instead.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Encrypt DNS challenge</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/scenarios/vps-lets-encrypt-dns-challenge/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/scenarios/vps-lets-encrypt-dns-challenge/index.html</guid>
      <description>This scenario covers a Traefik configuration for a public or private server. This uses Let’s Encrypt to sign TLS certificates, which are valid for use in most web browsers. This scenario will use the DNS-01 challenge type.&#xA;Info This scenario is good for public and private websites and services.&#xA;All Let’s Encrypt challenges leak domain names to public CT logs, however, with DNS-01 challenge we can use wildcards, so that only the root domain is leaked, not the exact hostnames.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Step-CA TLS challenge</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/scenarios/step-ca-tls-challenge/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/scenarios/step-ca-tls-challenge/index.html</guid>
      <description>This scenario covers a basic Traefik configuration for a public server (VPS). This uses Step-CA to sign off-grid TLS certificates. This scenario will use the TLS-ALPN-01 challenge type.&#xA;Step-CA is a self-hosted ACME provider, a root Certificate Authority. Step-CA is an alternative to Let’s Encrypt, but they do serve difference purposes:&#xA;Use Let’s Encrypt if you need “valid” certificates trusted by web browsers. Use Step-CA if you want fully self-hosted PKI, and your own Certificate Authority.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Step-CA DNS challenge</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/scenarios/step-ca-dns-challenge/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/scenarios/step-ca-dns-challenge/index.html</guid>
      <description>TODO</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wireguard layer 7 proxy</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/scenarios/wireguard-layer-7-server/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/scenarios/wireguard-layer-7-server/index.html</guid>
      <description>TODO</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wireguard layer 7 client</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/scenarios/wireguard-layer-7-client/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/scenarios/wireguard-layer-7-client/index.html</guid>
      <description>TODO</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wireguard layer 4 client</title>
      <link>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/scenarios/wireguard-layer-4-client/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://book.rymcg.tech/d.rymcg.tech/traefik-proxy/scenarios/wireguard-layer-4-client/index.html</guid>
      <description>TODO</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>